Guide to the Jonathan Solovy: Interviews for "Jewish American Volunteers and the Spanish Civil War" Audio Collection ALBA.AUDIO.101
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
Jonathan Solovy: Interviews for "Jewish American Volunteers and the Spanish Civil War"
1980-1981
ALBA.AUDIO.101
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
1.0 linear feet 53 audiocassettes
Solovy, Jonathan Stuart
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Jonathan Solovy, "Jewish American Volunteers and the Spanish Civil War: a study of tripartite identity" (Masters Thesis, University of Michigan, 1981) (copy at Tamiment Library; DP269.47.A46 S65 1981a)
Fredericka Martin Papers (ALBA 1)
Scope and Content
The collection consists of 53 audio cassettes which are interviews with Jewish American volunteers from the Spanish Civil War. The interviews were conducted as research for Solovy's thesis "Jewish American Volunteers and the Spanish Civil War: a Study of Tripartite Identity". They were conducted between 1980 and 1981.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions. Researcher is responsible for the cost of creating an access copy of any item.
For details E-mail: gail.malmgreen@nyu.edu
Historical/Biographical Note
Jonathan Solovy created these tapes in the course of research for his thesis "Jewish American Volunteers and the Spanish Civil War". Through contacts with vets such as Saul Wellman and Pete Smith, other veterans were contacted and interviewed. The interviews were conducted between 1980 and 1981.
Solovy, Jonathan Stuart; Americans |z Spain |x History |y 20th century.; Audiocassettes.; Spain |x History |y Civil War, 1936-1939 |x Participation, Jewish.
- Bessie, Alvah (tape 1 of 4), Oct 16, 1980 (Drawer 3, Cassette 101-002)
- Bessie, Alvah (tape 2 of 4), Oct 16, 1980 (Drawer 3, Cassette 101-002)
- Bessie, Alvah (tape 3 of 4), Oct 16, 1980 (Drawer 3, Cassette 101-003)
- Bessie, Alvah (tape 4 of 4), Oct 16, 1980 (Drawer 3, Cassette 101-004)
- Cohen, Milton, Aug 1, 1980 (Drawer 3, Cassette 101-005)
- Fishman, Moe (tape 1 of 3), Dec 28 - 29, 1980 (Drawer 3, Cassette 101-006)
- Fishman, Moe (tape 2 of 3), Dec 28 - 29, 1980 (Drawer 3, Cassette 101-007)
- Fishman, Moe (tape 3 of 3), Dec 28 - 29, 1980 (Drawer 3, Cassette 101-008)
- Gladnick, Robert (tape 1 of 4), Nov 3, 1980 (Drawer 3, Cassette 101-009, Box ALBA Shared Access Box 2)
- Gladnick, Robert (tape 2 of 4), Nov 3, 1980 (Drawer 3, Cassette 101-010, Box ALBA Shared Access Box 2)
- Gladnick, Robert (tape 3 of 4), Nov 3, 1980 (Drawer 3, Cassette 101-011, Box ALBA Shared Access Box 2)
- Gladnick, Robert (tape 4 of 4), Nov 3, 1980 (Drawer 3, Cassette 101-012, Box ALBA Shared Access Box 2)
- Harris, Sidney (tape 1 of 2), Aug 27, 1980 (Drawer 3, Cassette 101-013)
- Harris, Sidney (tape 2 of 2), Aug 27, 1980 (Drawer 3, Cassette 101-014)
- Hilkevitch, Aaron (tape 1 of 3), [1980?] (Drawer 3, Cassette 101-015)
- Hilkevitch, Aaron (tape 2 of 3), [1980?] (Drawer 3, Cassette 101-016)
- Hilkevitch, Aaron (tape 3 of 3), [1980?] (Drawer 3, Cassette 101-017)
- Lamb, Leonard (tape 1 of 3), Oct 26, 1980 (Drawer 3, Cassette 101-018)
- Lamb, Leonard (tape 2 of 3), Oct 26, 1980 (Drawer 3, Cassette 101-019)
- Lamb, Leonard (tape 3 of 3), Oct 26, 1980 (Drawer 3, Cassette 101-020)
- Lending, Edward (tape 1 of 3), Oct 19, 1980 (Drawer 3, Cassette 101-021)
- Lending, Edward (tape 2 of 3), Oct 19, 1980 (Drawer 3, Cassette 101-022)
- Lending, Edward (tape 3 of 3), Oct 19, 1980 (Drawer 3, Cassette 101-023)
- Linn, Sidney, [1980?] (Drawer 3, Cassette 101-024)
- Lossowski, Vincent (tape 1 of 3), Nov 15, 1980 (Drawer 3, Cassette 101-025)
- Lossowski, Vincent (tape 2 of 3), Nov 15, 1980 (Drawer 3, Cassette 101-026)
- Lossowski, Vincent ( tape 3 of 3), Nov 15, 1980 (Drawer 3, Cassette 101-027)
- Osheroff, Abe (tape 1 of 2), Sep 29, 1980 (Drawer 3, Cassette 101-028, Box ALBA Shared Access Box 2)
- Osheroff, Abe (tape 2 of 2), Sep 29, 1980 (Drawer 3, Cassette 101-029, Box ALBA Shared Access Box 2)
- Pike, William (tape 1 of 2), Apr 2, 1981 (Disk 3, Cassette 101-030)
- Pike, William (tape 2 of 2), Apr 2, 1981 (Drawer 3, Cassette 101-031)
- Prago, Albert, Nov 8, 1980 (Drawer 3, Cassette 101-032)
- Rossen, John, May 3, 1980 (Drawer 3, Cassette 101-033)
- Simon, John L. (tape 1 of 2), Jan 11, 1981 (Drawer 3, Cassette 101-034)
- Simon, John L. (tape 2 of 2), Jan 11, 1981 (Drawer 3, Cassette 101-035)
- Stamm, Morris (tape 1 of 3), Mar 29, 1981 (Drawer 3, Cassette 101-036)
- Stamm, Morris (tape 2 of 3), Mar 29, 1981 (Drawer 3, Cassette 101-037)
- Stamm, Morris (tape 3 of 3), Mar 29, 1981 (Drawer 3, Cassette 101-038)
- Susman, William (tape 1 of 2), Oct 4, 1980 (Drawer 3, Cassette 101-039)
- Susman, William (tape 2 of 2), Oct 4, 1980 (Drawer 3, Cassette 101-040)
- Watt, George (tape 1 of 4), [1980?] (Drawer 3, Cassette 101-041, Box ALBA Shared Access Box 2)
- Watt, George (tape 2 of 4), [1980?] (Drawer 3, Cassette 101-042, Box ALBA Shared Access Box 2)
- Watt, George (tape 3 of 4), [1980?] (Drawer 3, Cassette 101-043, Box ALBA Shared Access Box 2)
- Watt, George (tape 4 of 4), [1980?] (Drawer 3, Cassette 101-044, Box ALBA Shared Access Box 2)
- Wellman, Saul (tape 1 of 4), [1980?] (Drawer 3, Cassette 101-045)
- Wellman, Saul (tape 2 of 4), [1980?] (Drawer 3, Cassette 101-046)
- Wellman, Saul (tape 3 of 4), [1980?] (Drawer 3, Cassette 101-047)
- Wellman, Saul (tape 4 of 4), [1980?] (Drawer 3, Cassette 101-048)
- Zawadowski, Joseph (tape 1 of 5), Aug 5, 1980 (Drawer 3, Cassette 101-050)
- Zawadowski, Joseph (tape 2 of 5), Aug 5, 1980 (Drawer 3, Cassette 101-051)
- Zawadowski, Joseph (tape 3 of 5), Aug 5, 1980 (Drawer 3, Cassette 101-052)
- Zawadowski, Joseph (tape 4 of 5), Aug 5, 1980 (Drawer 3, Cassette 101-053)
- Zawadowski, Joseph (tape 5 of 5), Aug 5, 1980 (Drawer 3, Cassette 101-049)